<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Notes</title><link>/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Notes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 16:09:34 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basics of curl command</title><link>/posts/curl-basics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 20:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/curl-basics/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all might have used the curl command but might be unaware of it. It&amp;rsquo;s super old&lt;br&gt;
and still serves a great purpose. It has been available since 1996 and still is&lt;br&gt;
widely used in many embedded technologies, web API testing, CLI applications,&lt;br&gt;
etc. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll see some basics of using the curl command along with&lt;br&gt;
its applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-the-curl-command"&gt;What is the curl command?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curl or cURL command is the utility or tool to access the internet from the command&lt;br&gt;
line interface using various protocols. This looks trivial but it can blow up&lt;br&gt;
your mind! Most people use this tool for fetching and processing the&lt;br&gt;
data from the servers/internet from their terminal without the browser but&lt;br&gt;
there is a lot more to it. It is used in various embedded devices for accessing&lt;br&gt;
the network in a lightweight and accessible way. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how you can use the curl&lt;br&gt;
command from the very basics.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Vim: Terminal Integration</title><link>/posts/vim-plus-teminal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 15:21:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/vim-plus-teminal/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vim-and-terminal"&gt;Vim and Terminal!?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim was made to work with the command line. Many beginners do not understand what are the true capabilities of Vim, myself included:) Vim can run terminal commands without leaving the text editor, open an instance of a terminal, work with shell environments, and other things depending on the use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="running-terminal-shell-commands-from-within-vim"&gt;Running Terminal/ shell commands from within Vim&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can run the commands from inside of Vim by just using &lt;code&gt;:!&lt;/code&gt; before the command, this means you have to be in command mode. Just after being in command mode, the ! or bang operator will execute the command typed after it from the terminal(Linux/ macOS) or your default shell(Windows -&amp;gt; CMD/Powershell).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>