<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Substack on Notes</title><link>/tags/substack/</link><description>Recent content in Substack on Notes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 22:25:30 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/substack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #77</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-77/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:45:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-77/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #77&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a harsh week. Not the roughest yet tiny exhilarating with new hopes. It happens, to get the best of me, things will come towards me with force. I am welcome to those challenges and hurdles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am in awe and inspired to build things, I went off track last week. The previous week I was pumped with two side project in a day, yet slumped then. This week would like to build that momentum back.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #76</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-76/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:45:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-76/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #76&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a good start to the year, finally doing something that I had struggled to do for the past year or so. AI Assisted Programming. Yeah! That was something I finally somewhat understand, and can do it without feeling a slightest of grudge or emotional drama. It took a while to realize it, but here we are. 2026!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know how I feel right now. Its quite a good times to be in tech.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #75</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-75/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 18:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-75/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #75&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh the middle of end of 2025, and the beginning of 2026. This is a wired post. I let myself back, reflected more. I know it was a fast paced year for software development. People are here to prove it. I just laid it out straight that its never been valuable to be a human, a distinct, natural and earnest human.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I must say I completed a non-technical goal of 2025, I have my novel&amp;#8217;s first draft in my hands(in my google drive). Its very rough, I want to revise it, I want to remove the fluff, but it is there in its entirety. 33 Chapters, 85K words. 45 days of writing span across 6 months, I did it. I am pumped to revise and write the next novel. The hunger to write has never been higher for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #74</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-74/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:45:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-74/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #74&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was winding down week, 2025, ending slowly, the biggest irony. The year was full of fast-paced, unprecedented models just dropping here and there. It was hard to keep up with the progress. It was getting overwhelming, no one is used to such a level of information. I was dreading with so much power in our hands. I couldn&amp;#8217;t handle it and refrained it and thought it was better to focus on learning new things. I kept using AI tools at work, not by choice, but initially through force but then through necessity. &lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #73</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-73/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-73/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week 73&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A pretty slow and sluggish week, but some momentum carried in the end. There was a disappointment after a glimmer of excitement when gemini 3 Flash dropped for the experiments that I was running for extraction of documents. It was maybe just the timing, but after this seeing code execution from chats, it was amazing. A good end to the work week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have continued to write Advent of SQL for the past 4 days, and brought back the streak of writing &lt;a href="https://meetgor.com/sqlog"&gt;SQLog&lt;/a&gt;. I was not able to ship some code over the past weekend. But this weekend, I am pumped. I have time sorted out. Would be shipping some improvements in the website. Oh! I actually added snowball and particles based on season on &lt;a href="meetgor.com"&gt;my website&lt;/a&gt; (only index and post pages).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #72</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-72/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:45:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-72/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #72&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A good productive week (I am not sure, I am saying that in the last month of 2025). I would be writing a yearly review in a couple of weeks and this week might lift my spirits up. I was fresh, given time off from work, not really, but given the time to experiment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read a lot, fiction, technical, even philosophical, and random Hacker News articles. I read 2 books of Harry Potter. I haven&amp;#8217;t read Harry Potter, I have watched the first 3 movies, but not books. I enjoyed it, it was subtly different from movies, I missed the quote &amp;#8220;What an Idiot&amp;#8221; from the movies, it was not in the book, i was disappointed but the atmospheric adventures was amazing read.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #71</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-71/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:45:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-71/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #71&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a roller-coaster week. Half of the week, it was travelling and outside. The rest was coping with AI news and code agents. Getting back to work after a week is a bit stressful and brings a bit of hurdle of health. I wasn&amp;#8217;t quite well for a couple of days after the trip, and couldn&amp;#8217;t really work at my 100% best. So, this weekend I would be pacing up, slowing down when needed to rest with ease. I have a few plans for Advent of Code, I haven&amp;#8217; gotten the time to solve even the first problem, looking forward to the weekend to keeping up with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #70</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-70/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:07:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-70/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Week #70&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I wrote last week, I would be travelling and out on a break due to weddings at my contry side place, cousins wedding, som heavy travelling no tech access for most of the time. However I had atleast 4 days of work covered so I have few tidbits to share. Weekends, three days of the week and taking leave on evening on wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I played around with vllms , new different models for different thins ranging from ad hock coding tasks, proper code editing, and document extraction usecases. Didn&amp;#8217;t find time to read or watch much.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #69</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-69/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:45:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-69/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #69&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a good week. That&amp;#8217;s what I can say. I continued writing. I experimented with quite a lot of things. VLLMs, new models, new approaches, tactics, and read a lot of articles as usual.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I was in the GCP Cloud Log Explorer TUI in the bubbletea golang app, I vibe-coded it, I wanted to feel it. No, I am not using that to publish on GitHub. I would make one from bare hands, what to put in the model, on the screen, when to update what, which keybindings to add where, I will think about each of them and code from scratch. My goal is to learn and build, not just build.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #68</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-68/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:45:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-68/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #68&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a great week. A consistent clean week. I wrote around 9k words on my project. I feel good again. I didn&amp;#8217;t do much on the weekends as usual. I am slowing down. I did a lot of things at work, experiments, and more experiments on VLLMs and parsing documents. It&amp;#8217;s fun times. I think for this weekend, I have plans as this post will cover what my mind is fixated on for the moment, Golang and TUIs, and a pain that is daily buzzing me, cleaning log files to get the actual data. LLMs are good at it, but take a bit of time for such trivial things.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #67</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-67/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:45:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-67/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #67&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a slow and steady week. New habits are emerging. It was a pleasant experience, I felt good, I kept myself out of the social media and content spiral doom-scrolling. Why? Because something changed the perspective of action and effect, the piece I was missing was intention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Action, Intention, and Effect&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I heard or read somewhere, that we feel anxious or we waste our time, not because of motivation, rather due to the lack of intentionality of the actions. If you are going to the web with a clear focus and a objective, no force or urge can stop you. Motivation helps but doesn&amp;#8217;t carry you all the way. Its not one emotion or quality thing, rather all-hands together approach. You solely can&amp;#8217;t rely on focus either, you need your inner fire, you need purpose, you need energy, you need the skills to do it. Nothing comes on its own with a single cause-effect, its a multi-dimensional world of action and effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #66</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-66/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:45:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-66/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Week #66&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a silent week, chipping away the days like wasted days. I didn&amp;#8217;t do much, honestly, it was tiring and draining. I spent the weekend outside, had a few chores to complete, and didn&amp;#8217;t quite get the time to sit at peace. This weekend too, looks the same. Post Diwali rituals, guests, and functions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have long left the SQLog to decay, but I intend to pick it back up from tomorrow. Lot of things to do, little mental energy left.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #65</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-65/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:45:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-65/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #65&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A happy gloom Diwali, gone in a woosh. We are in a different year. 2082 Vikram Samvat, If you are into that. Felt a bit sad, a bit happy. Not sure what the next year might have in offer. Hopefully it would be for the good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compared to last tear, I find myself happier, but lost at the same time. I have found a cure to my writing slump atlast and trying to wrestle a writing routine. It looks a bit promising, 2 months to end 2025, still a comeback on the edge. This year was wild, I had severe anxiety and it kept throwing AI LLM Models every day, all day. Each day felt like waking up from existential crisis, but here I am writing it, the sixty fifth edition. More to come.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #64</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-64/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:45:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-64/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #64&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a pretty busy week, not from a work perspective but from the chaotic household perspective. It is Diwali this weekend and next week. So, the preparations, the cleaning of homes, were done past weekend. It actually took my whole Sunday, sweet Sunday, and even half of Saturday. Hh! I read a lot of books, though. I found a great book that fits the vibe I wanted while being in the atmosphere of Diwali.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #63</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-63/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 18:45:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-63/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #63&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a fun week. After a long, a long I have had the time to rip-off a code base hands on and do something beyond pushing a feature, it was about reforming how a thing is approached. I felt really good. There are always rough days, but these days, the days that give you pain but that pain is satisfying. At the end of each day of the week, I had gone and came out of bed brimming full of ideas and questions to talk and sit through. Felt I was back to the grind.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #62</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-62/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 18:45:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-62/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #62&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a great week. I didn&amp;#8217;t knew I would say that at the start of the week. But hell yes, a promotion, finally. A hope at the end of the tunnel. Hard work pays off in the end. I kept believing and finally able to bring smile on my loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I quoted last week about home, a family, is not something that is by blood, rather it is the group of people who strive for each others success, for uplifting each other, when one falls down the other roots for him or her, when its harsh time, everyone steps back and stays together. And I was able to experience just that. The true value and meaning of a family and life.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #61</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-61/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:45:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-61/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #61&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bit of slow and disappointing week on a personal note. I tried my best to be a backend developer but was not worthy of being one, I was stranded as a product developer. I am not saying I hate being a product developer, it just gets too menial and boring once you know the limitations and the quirks of a product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apart from the grill, I learnt a lot about tokenization. I also continued to write occasionally about SQLite in the SQLog, three more entries. Wasn&amp;#8217;t able to livestream due to guests and was unwell for the weekend with cold.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #60</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-60/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 18:45:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-60/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Weekly #60&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another great week, consistently learning SQL, developing another streak for solving problems on FreeCodeCamp with Javascript and Python, reading instead of doomscrolling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been learning about SQL since maybe 10 weeks now and finding myself in a good position, for the past 4 weeks I have written posts every day and it has helped me get back to the technical writing flow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the work side, it was a fun week, tinkering with a system that is already working decently and wanted it to get the most of it, turning the bits and knobs of a system is so cool. &lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #59</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-59/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 18:45:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-59/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #59&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another productive week, a lot shipped, almost all critical bugs fixed, the launch looks great. Wrote daily for another week about SQLite/SQL. Adding up 24 posts. Read it &lt;a href="https://www.meetgor.com/sqlog/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Generating a lot of ideas, getting back to journaling, reading instead of consuming videos and doomscrolling. It is getting better day by day. I have completed my yearly goal of reading 12 books. Still 3 more months to go, would be almost at 15-18 books.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Techstructive Weekly #58</title><link>/posts/techstructive-weekly-58/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 18:45:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-weekly-58/</guid><description>&lt;h2&gt;Week #58&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What a week, almost broke prod for half an hour! On Monday, can you believe it? I didn&amp;#8217;t but that was a bug. Patched it and moved on. Had a consistent posting and learning sessions daily for an hour about SQL and SQLite. Feels good. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Had an situation where knowing javascript was a big deal and I don&amp;#8217;t feel like writing javascript, it just doesn&amp;#8217;t appeal to me, I guess I have to amp that up. Anyways, one more reason added for hating javascript, its unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>