<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hashnode on Notes</title><link>/tags/hashnode/</link><description>Recent content in Hashnode on Notes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 16:09:34 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/hashnode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2022: Year Review</title><link>/posts/2022-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022-review/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, what a year! If 2021 was a start, 2022 was a year to convert a start into a goal. From collaborating on open-source projects to getting an internship, it was an exciting year! Created a couple dozen of projects(not finished as usual), wrote 40+ articles, did a couple of streams, learned the basics of golang, and spend 6 months as a backend dev intern at &lt;a href="https://thesolarlabs.com/"&gt;Solarlabs&lt;/a&gt;, just a year that was awaited for the hard work over the span of 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Podevcast: A single source for developer podcasts</title><link>/posts/podevcast-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 22:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/podevcast-project/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Developers! Want to listen to programming podcasts from a single place? Podevcast is the place you should be searching for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am Meet Gor and I present this project as a submission to the Netlify x Hashnode Hackathon. Podevcast is a webpage(static) for listening to podcasts centered around developers and programming. Just pick your favorite one and start listening straight away. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the making of Podevcast. Head on to &lt;a href="https://podevcast.netlify.app/"&gt;https://podevcast.netlify.app/&lt;/a&gt; to check out the live app.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What is Machine Learning?</title><link>/posts/ml-intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 15:30:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/ml-intro/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all hear about terms like &lt;code&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/code&gt;, and others, but what do they actually mean and why do you need to care about these as a developer. This won&amp;rsquo;t be a perfect guide in terms of experience but surely enough to get anyone through the basics of Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the kind of article I write but, having such challenges can help me become a better technical writer, this is the challenge put forward in the Hashnode Bootcamp 4 to get out of my comfort zone. Here&amp;rsquo;s my take on what I know about Machine Learning till now (P.S. Half of the stuff I discovered and re-learned during writing).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What's in Techstructive Blog</title><link>/posts/techstructive-blog-init/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 15:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/techstructive-blog-init/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello World!&lt;/strong&gt; This is an article in which I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce why Techstructive Blog exists and what it covers in brief. This is just a casual introduction to my blogging niche. P.S. It&amp;rsquo;s not any technical blog but has challenged me enough to write and complete it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Techstructive Blog is my personal blog hosted on GitHub pages as well as on &lt;a href="https://techstructiveblog.hashnode.dev/"&gt;Hashnode&lt;/a&gt;. It first started on Hashnode and soon created my own using Jekyll on GitHub pages. On this blog, I write articles mainly Vim, BASH, and some programming languages and tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Journey as a Technical Writer</title><link>/posts/technical-writer-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 19:30:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/technical-writer-journey/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello World! I am Meet Gor, a self-taught web developer, Linux enthusiast, and a newbie technical writer. I am currently studying in an Engineering college pursuing my B. Tech in I.T. I love to explore new programming languages and technologies, create innovative projects, love to write stories and blogs like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-it-started"&gt;How it started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was learning Vim, I found the need to write some kind of cheatsheet for myself. So I started writing it, soon I realized I had written a kind of an article instead of a cheatsheet XD There were a lot of chunks of it unorganized but meaningful in some sense. So, from there I started to research on article writing. I found the term perfect for my techno feelings to express i.e. &amp;ldquo;Technical Writing&amp;rdquo;. I soon landed on Hashnode, I knew Medium, GeeksforGeeks but found Hashnode absolutely perfect and much more viable to the creativity of an author.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dev Quotes: A platform for developers to quote and get inspired - Auth0 x Hashnode Hackathon</title><link>/posts/devquotes-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 23:45:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/devquotes-platform/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one can understand the joy in finishing a personal project, except the dreamer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a while,since I have posted an article here, as I was busy on a project or a hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, world! I am Meet a student and a self-taught web developer. I like to make and break stuff, especially when it comes to programming and Linux. I like shell scripting and learning different languages at once, love to learn about Vim and Linux everyday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>