<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Django on Notes</title><link>/tags/django/</link><description>Recent content in Django on Notes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:49:51 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/django/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a Chat Application with Django and HTMX</title><link>/posts/django-htmx-chat-app/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-htmx-chat-app/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="django--htmx-chat-application"&gt;Django + HTMX Chat application&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will be creating a Django project, which will be a chat-room kind of application. The user needs to authenticate to the app and then and there he/she can create or join rooms, every room will have some name and URL associated with it. So, the user simply needs to enter the name of the room, which will be unique. The user can then simply enter the messages in the chat room. This is a core chat application that uses web sockets.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Create a Non-Clustered Index in Django with Postgres as DB</title><link>/posts/django-non-clustered-index-pg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-non-clustered-index-pg/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-a-non-clustered-index"&gt;What is a non-clustered index?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A non-clustered index is a seperate structure than an actual table in the database, it stores the non-clustered index key(the column which we want to sort in the table), and a pointer to the actual values based on the index key. So, non-clustered indexes do not change the physical order of the table records, instead it holds a structure that can provide a easier and distinct way to fetch objects based on a particular column as the primary key in the structure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Bulk Update QuerySet objects</title><link>/posts/django-bulk-update-queryset/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-bulk-update-queryset/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say, I have a lots of objects which I want to update with a particular field or fields. We can use the &lt;a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/4.1/ref/models/querysets/#bulk-update"&gt;bulk_update&lt;/a&gt; method with the model name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"&gt;&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python"&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#75715e"&gt;# blog/models.py&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; django.db &lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; models
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;ARTICLE_STATUS &lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; [
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt; (&lt;span style="color:#e6db74"&gt;&amp;#34;PUBLISHED&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#e6db74"&gt;&amp;#34;Published&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;),
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt; (&lt;span style="color:#e6db74"&gt;&amp;#34;DRAFT&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#e6db74"&gt;&amp;#34;Draft&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;),
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef"&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e"&gt;Article&lt;/span&gt;(models&lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Model):
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt; title &lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; models&lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;CharField(max_length&lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff"&gt;128&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt; description &lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; models&lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;CharField(max_length&lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff"&gt;512&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt; content &lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; models&lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;TextField()
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt; status &lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; models&lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;CharField(max_length&lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff"&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;, choices&lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;ARTICLE_STATUS, default&lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#e6db74"&gt;&amp;#34;DRAFT&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e"&gt;__str__&lt;/span&gt;(self):
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; self&lt;span style="color:#f92672"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;title
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have a simple model &lt;code&gt;Article&lt;/code&gt; with a few typical attributes like &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;description&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;status&lt;/code&gt;. We have the status as a choice field from two options as &lt;code&gt;Draft&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Published&lt;/code&gt;. It could be a boolean field, but that looks too gross for a article status.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django-Mermaid</title><link>/posts/django-mermaid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 16:44:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-mermaid/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Create ER Diagrams (Entity Relationship Diagrams) of your Django projects related to different models of associated applications in Mermaid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech Stack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django: Get list of all models and associated fields in a django project</title><link>/posts/django-list-models/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-list-models/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say we want the list of all the models and associated attributes in all the applications of a django project, we can do that using the &lt;a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/4.0/ref/applications/"&gt;django.apps&lt;/a&gt; with apps method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="get-all-the-models-in-a-project"&gt;Get all the models in a project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fetch all the models, we can use the &lt;a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/4.0/ref/applications/#django.apps.AppConfig.get_models"&gt;get_models&lt;/a&gt; methods, it will return a list of model classes in all the entire project(all applications). We can import all the models in the django project with the command:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Blog DevLog: Load Frontmatter data into Template/Model Form Fields</title><link>/posts/django-form-load-frontmatter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-form-load-frontmatter/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an Article Form where I load my post into it directly, it might have frontmatter. So what I wish to achieve is when I paste in the content, the frontmatter should be picked up and it should render the form fields like &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;description&lt;/code&gt;, and then also remove the frontmatter from the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do that, we will require a model to work with and a form based on that model. We will exclude a few fields from that model so as to process these attributes on the server side. I am working on my Blog project which is a simple Django application. You can get the source code for the project on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/mr-destructive/techstructive-blog/"&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django + HTMX CRUD application</title><link>/posts/django-htmx-crud/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-htmx-crud/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gone are the days of writing Ajax requests with javascript, just add a few parameters to the HTML content tags and you will be ready for sending requests to your backend. So, we are going back in time and correcting the way we think of APIs and client/server-side rendering. We are referring to the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypermedia"&gt;Hypermedia model&lt;/a&gt; for levering the server-side processing of data. Let&amp;rsquo;s get our feets wet with this ancient but revolutionary methodology of development with &lt;a href="https://htmx.org/"&gt;HTMX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying Django Project with Railway Nixpacks</title><link>/posts/django-deploy-railway-nixpacks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-deploy-railway-nixpacks/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have seen how to deploy a Django application on railway app in the &lt;a href="https://www.meetgor.com/django-deploy-railway/"&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href="https://www.meetgor.com/series/django-deployment/"&gt;series&lt;/a&gt;. We deployed the django project using the Heroku Buildpacks under the hood. The railway app provides a couple of options on how to build your web application. Currently, there are three options, one of which is the &lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/heroku-20-stack"&gt;heroku buildpacks&lt;/a&gt; which is the default one, second, we have the nixpacks which we will see today, and the third is the &lt;a href="https://paketo.io/"&gt;Paketo buildpack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>DJ Notes</title><link>/posts/djnotes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 16:44:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/djnotes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A note taking application with features like markdown, syntax highlighting and filtering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech Stack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django App from Scratch Using Docker with Debian Base Image</title><link>/posts/django-app-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-app-from-scratch/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="pull-a-fresh-debian-image"&gt;Pull a Fresh Debian Image&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a docker container from a Debian image, the following command can be used to pull a debain 11-slim image and create a container of it, also enter into the container in a interactive environment &lt;code&gt;-it&lt;/code&gt; mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex="0"&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run -v $(pwd):/var/www --rm -it -p 8001:80 debian:11-slim
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id="create-a-django-app-from-shell-script"&gt;Create a Django App from Shell script&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, since we are inside a Debian container, we can enter a few commands, you can refer to the Mark Gibney&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://github.com/no-gravity/web_app_from_scratch"&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; for the script.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Project with PostgreSQL Deployment on Railway App</title><link>/posts/django-deploy-railway/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-deploy-railway/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have already seen the process of deployment of a Django app on Heroku, now we can move to another platform which is &lt;a href="https://railway.app"&gt;Railway App&lt;/a&gt;. This allows a faster and more intuitive way to deploy a Django app(or any sort of web app). This platform has several &lt;a href="https://railway.app/starters"&gt;Starter Apps&lt;/a&gt; for shipping your app in several clicks, definitely, it would require some configuration and tweaking a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be following similar steps from the &lt;a href="https://mr-destructive.github.io/techstructive-blog/series/django-deployment/"&gt;Django-Heroku Deployment Guide&lt;/a&gt; for configuring and setting up our Django project for the deployment on the Railway app. We explore a few different ways to create and deploy a Django project on Railway.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django + PostgreSQL Deployment on Heroku</title><link>/posts/django-deploy-heroku/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-deploy-heroku/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django projects are quite easy to build and simple to understand, you might have created a Django application and wanted to show it to the world? You can deploy a basic Django application with a database(PostgreSQL) with Heroku. It provides a decent free tier with some great features and add-ons. A free tier Heroku account has a limitation of 5 apps, limited data in the database, limited connections to the server per month, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dockerize a Django project</title><link>/posts/dockerize-django-prj/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 19:12:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dockerize-django-prj/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="dockerize-a-django-project"&gt;Dockerize a Django project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can run our Django projects in a Docker Container by creating a Docker image for our project. It is really easy and intuitive to create a Dockerfile for any given application as it really is a matter of writing commands in a file and basically running it is a isolated environment. To create a Docker image, we first need a Dockerfile. A Dockerfile is simply a Blueprint to create a image in Docker. In this file we specify the instructions/commands/environment variables to create a image for our app to run.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Basics: CRUD API</title><link>/posts/django-basics-crud-api/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 23:45:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-basics-crud-api/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After understanding the admin section and setting up a database, we can finally move on to the CRUD API in Django. We will create a API in pure Django with Model Form, Class Based Views and templates. We will go in two parts in this section, first revising the workflow of the app creation and setup, the next part all about CRUD API. We&amp;rsquo;ll dive into a lot of familiar topics and concepts from previous parts but there are is still a lot to learn beyond the basics.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BackChat</title><link>/posts/backchat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/backchat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A simple chat/messaging app created for exploring HTMX and django-channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech Stack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django-Channels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daphne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTMX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Basics: Admin Section</title><link>/posts/django-basics-admin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 22:25:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-basics-admin/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous section, we configured the database in our Django project. We will move ahead and interact with the Admin Section in Django. Django has a built-in Admin Section which we can use to manage our apps and models. We will create a admin account(superuser) and try to render our custom Model in the Admin Interface. We shall further discuss the customization in the Admin section as per our requirements and necessity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Basics: Database Configurations</title><link>/posts/django-database-conf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 16:40:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-database-conf/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this part of the series, we will create an external database and configure the settings for that database. We also look into the process of migrations which is to convert a model which we created in the previous part into the actual structure/schema for the database. I&amp;rsquo;ll be using &lt;code&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/code&gt; for most of the demonstrations but it should be similar for other database management tools. This part will make your Django project link to a local database.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Basics: Creating Models</title><link>/posts/django-basics-models/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 22:15:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-basics-models/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have seen the basics of Django templating in the previous parts of the series. Now, we can move on to the more backend stuff in Django which deals with the Databases, queries, admin section, and so on. In this particular part, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the fundamental part of any application in Django i.e the &lt;code&gt;Model&lt;/code&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ll understand what the model is, how to structure one, how to create relationships and add constraints on the fields, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Basics: Static Files</title><link>/posts/django-basics-static-files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 22:45:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-basics-static-files/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After creating templates, it should be rather tempting to add some styles and logic to them. Well yes, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how to add static files in a web application using django. Static files are not only CSS, but also media/images and Javascript files as well. In this part of the series, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the basics of working with static files in django including the configuration, rendering and storing of the static files.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Basics: Templates</title><link>/posts/django-basics-templates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 16:45:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-basics-templates/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After learning the basics of views and URLs, we can now move on to the next concept i.e. Templates. In Django, Templates are quite an important component for the application as it acts as the &lt;code&gt;frontend&lt;/code&gt; for the web application. With the help of templates and some features provided by Django, it becomes very intuitive and simple to make dynamic web content.&lt;br&gt;
In this part, we understand what are templates and what is the way to render them.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Basics: Views and URLS</title><link>/posts/django-basics-views-urls/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 12:03:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-basics-views-urls/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting familiar with the folder structure of the Django framework, we&amp;rsquo;ll create our first view in an app. The basics of creating and mapping a view with a URL will be cleared by the end of this part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="creating-views"&gt;Creating Views&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Views are the functions written in python as a logic control unit of the webserver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a view or typically-like function, we need to write a function in the &lt;code&gt;views.py&lt;/code&gt; file inside of the application folder. The function name can be anything but should be a sensible name as far as its usability is concerned. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a basic example of sending an HTTP response of &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Basics: Folder Structure</title><link>/posts/django-basics-folder-struct/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 15:45:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-basics-folder-struct/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After setting up the development for the Django framework, we will explore the project structure. In this part, we understand the structure along with the various components in the Project as well as individual apps. We will understand the objective of each file and folder in a brief and hopefully by the end of this part, you&amp;rsquo;ll be aware of how the Django project is structured and get a good overview of the flow of development in the Django project.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Basics: Setup and Installation</title><link>/posts/django-basics-setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 16:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-basics-setup/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crucial aspect of starting to learn any framework is the ease to set it up and Django by far is the easiest of the options out there. There is just a few lines of code to install django if you already have python installed in your system. In this article, we see how to setup a django project along with a virtual environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have python and pip installed, you can move on to the &lt;a href="#setting-up-virtual-environment-in-python"&gt;virtual environment setup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Basics: What is it?</title><link>/posts/django-basics-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 20:45:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-basics-intro/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Django Basics series, in this series we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the basics of the Django web framework. In this part, we&amp;rsquo;ll understand what this web framework provides and what actually the back-end development consists of. We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss where Django is used and why it is a great choice for beginners as well as experienced developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-django"&gt;What is Django?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/Server-side/Django/Introduction"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; is a back-end web framework. It is based on python which means you have to write most of the project&amp;rsquo;s code in Python. But Django comes with a lot of boilerplate code and thus it becomes quite quick in the development.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Flask and Django - the backend web frameworks</title><link>/posts/flask-django-frameworks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 19:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/flask-django-frameworks/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have seen the buzz around web frameworks like Django, Flask, Node.js, etc but have you taken time to learn all of them? No, and you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t! Because many web frameworks share the same principle and workflow with a bit of difference. It&amp;rsquo;s just like learning one programming language and applying the same concepts in a different syntax and mechanism. In the world of web frameworks, this is the case as well, but most of them will disagree with it as every web framework is unique in its design and that&amp;rsquo;s true, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django + Auth0 Quick Setup</title><link>/posts/djagno-auth0-script/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 20:08:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/djagno-auth0-script/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a guide and a walkthrough of how to quickly set up a base Django project with Auth0 as integration for authentication and authorization. I will walk you through the Django setup and how to use and integrate the functionalities of the Auth0. I will also discuss how why you should be using Auth0 and why I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script takes &lt;code&gt;2:44&lt;/code&gt; minutes time to do everything from scratch. From installing virtualenv in python to integrating the Auth0 application.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dev Quotes: A platform for developers to quote and get inspired - Auth0 x Hashnode Hackathon</title><link>/posts/devquotes-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 23:45:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/devquotes-platform/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one can understand the joy in finishing a personal project, except the dreamer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a while,since I have posted an article here, as I was busy on a project or a hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, world! I am Meet a student and a self-taught web developer. I like to make and break stuff, especially when it comes to programming and Linux. I like shell scripting and learning different languages at once, love to learn about Vim and Linux everyday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>DevQuotes</title><link>/posts/dev-quotes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 23:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dev-quotes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A simple quote/post sharing app created for exploring Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech Stack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Django Quick Setup Script</title><link>/posts/django-setup-script/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 18:50:46 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/django-setup-script/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you learn something very neatly and understand it very clearly, it feels like you are wasting time doing things over and over again. Same things in setting up a Django project, you feel like you could save those typing minutes by making a script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will make a script a batch script for windows and a BASH script for Linux/macOS. We will make a virtual environment using python and then install the libraries and dependencies like in this case we will install Django. You can also tinker with these scripts and install other dependencies if you want like Django rest framework, crispy forms, markdown, Redis, etc. We will also make a Django project using the positional parameter passed before running the script from the command line.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>World Atlas</title><link>/posts/world-atlas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 16:44:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/world-atlas/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A simple word game using some django in the backend and javascript for frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech stack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django-Rest-Framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Javascript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django rest framework as an api for most of the operations in the game like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validating a user input place from database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listing out all places from a given letter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a random place from a given letter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRUD endpoint for the places in the database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;API Link: &lt;a href="https://djangonaut.pythonanywhere.com/world-atlas/api/"&gt;https://djangonaut.pythonanywhere.com/world-atlas/api/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>