<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Link on Notes</title><link>/type/link/</link><description>Recent content in Link on Notes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:45:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/type/link/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why we have inflated expectations, 6 feet 7 inches</title><link>/posts/what-is-6-feet-7-inches/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:12:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/what-is-6-feet-7-inches/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is so true&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 1990s, a “middle-class job” was enough to buy a house. Being “6 feet” was enough to be tall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2020s, the middle has been hollowed out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be “wealthy” now requires a crypto-exit or a tech IPO (The Economic 6’7”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be “famous” requires global virality (The Social 6’7”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be “attractive” requires filters and surgery (The Aesthetic 6’7”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Printf Debugging in Go with Q</title><link>/posts/q-but-for-go-printf-debugging/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:05:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/q-but-for-go-printf-debugging/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is cool, we make logging a mess. For logs we need to have separate scripts to get relevant data. How much chaos it can be.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>On not using Django in 2026 due to AI?</title><link>/posts/on-not-using-django-in-2026/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 11:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/on-not-using-django-in-2026/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t quite get it. Maybe its true. Django provided a good start but then it was like a lock in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With LLMs its quite easy to generate the boilerplatey code that django provides out of the box, so that demand is lost?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its not the only reason django is here right? It has extensions, best python community and even more best documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it will be the best framework to build with LLMs in the future if the ecosystem continues to improve&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fear is not advocacy</title><link>/posts/ai-advocacy-should-not-be-fear-or-fomo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:46:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ai-advocacy-should-not-be-fear-or-fomo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is real advice. People are hyping about the next workflow to 100x our productivity. Its ok to be 1x and still push less bugs than 100x and push 1000 bugs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Distinguishing yourself early in your career as a developer</title><link>/posts/distinguish-yourself-as-a-developer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:42:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/distinguish-yourself-as-a-developer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is cool advice. I like writing, side projects, oss, reading, and making stuff. It just shows the passionate flowing out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The fear of not growing due to AI</title><link>/posts/fear-of-not-growing-due-to-ai/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:18:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fear-of-not-growing-due-to-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ah! This is a developer trying to love his craft, yet the people are cruel to not respect it. They just want to solve problems; no one cares, they are right, but empathy is traded for business value.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>you have everything you need</title><link>/posts/you-have-everything-and-nothing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:11:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/you-have-everything-and-nothing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Man, that was a heck of an article to read. I continued reading it because I found it relatable to Minecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You open a world, you have an empty inventory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still you believe you can win the game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without anything, &amp;ldquo;Kya lekar aya jagath me, kya lekar jayega&amp;rdquo; vibes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True, read it, it will change your perspective on reasoning for failure in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Interstitial Journaling</title><link>/posts/interstitial-journaling/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:01:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/interstitial-journaling/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is cool, maybe a little too much time aware, maybe doing it too much is bad, but still, a good way to break the mental procrastination cycle&lt;br&gt;
I think we can get a idea or get aware of the amount of time we wasted or done something good, and act on it accordingly. A nice trick for the brain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9:45: Wrap up the standup&lt;br&gt;
9:54: Log clearing&lt;br&gt;
10:15: Call with manager about the task&lt;br&gt;
10:33: Felt bad&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>GitHub - davidfowl/tally: Let agents classify your bank transactions.</title><link>/posts/tally-transaction-ai-tool/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:29:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tally-transaction-ai-tool/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A cool tool to check how it made it&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>